const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",a=200,i=120,t=[{id:121,question:"Which of the following is found in cotton",option:{a:"Starch",b:"Cellulose",c:"fat",d:"oil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:109,question:"The metal that liberates hydrogen from cold water in bubbles only is",option:{a:"Na",b:"K",c:"Ca",d:"Al"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:234,question:"A degree in atomic size and an increase in knuckler charge across a period lead to",option:{a:"A decrease in covalency in bond formation",b:"An increase in chemical reactivity",c:"An increase in the tendency to loss electrons",d:"A decrease in electro positivity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:85,question:"When cathode rays are detected onto the electrode of an electrometer, the instrument becomes",option:{a:"Negatively charged",b:"Positively charged",c:"Neutral",d:"Bipolar"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:230,question:"2C2H2(g)  +  5O2(g)     4CO2(g)  +  2H2O(g) In the reaction, the mass of carbon (IV) oxide produced on burning 78g of ethyne is [C = 12, O = 16, H = 1]",option:{a:"39",b:"352g",c:"264g",d:"156g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:246,question:"Which of the following results in the fall of acid rain",option:{a:"Gaseous hydrocarbons",b:"Oxide of lead",c:"Particulate matter",d:"Oxides of sulphur"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:94,question:"A charge in the temperature of a saturated solution disturbs the equilibrium between the",option:{a:"Dissolved solute and the solvent",b:"Solvent and the undissolved solute",c:"Dissolved solute and the undissolved solute",d:"Dissolved solute and the solution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:194,question:"How many hydrogen atoms does a single ring cycloalkane have less than the corresponding open- chain alkane",option:{a:"Three",b:"One",c:"Four",d:"Two"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:111,question:"The modern process of manufacturing steel from iron is by",option:{a:"Treatment with acids",b:"Oxidation",c:"Blast reduction",d:"Treatment with alkalis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:81,question:"The noble gases owe their inactivity to",option:{a:"Octet configuration",b:"Cyclic shape",c:"Hexagonal shape",d:"Obtuse configuration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:40,question:"A burning candle produces water and",option:{a:"Carbon(II)oxide",b:"Carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Oxygen",d:"Hydrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:291,question:"When iron is exposed to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Anahydrous  iron (III) oxide",b:"Anhydrous iron (II) oxide",c:"Hydrated iron (II) oxide",d:"Hydrated iron  (III) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:129,question:"A given volume of methane diffuses in 20s. how long will it take the same volume of sulphur(IV) oxide to diffuse under the same conditions    [C = 12, H = 1, S = 32, O = 16]",option:{a:"5s",b:"20s",c:"40s",d:"60s"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:130,question:"An electron can be added to a halogen atom to form a halide ion with",option:{a:"2 valence electrons",b:"3 valence electrons",c:"7 valence electrons",d:"Valence electrons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:240,question:"CH3-CH2-C = CH  The hybridization in the compound above is",option:{a:"Sp3 and sp",b:"Sp3 and sp2",c:"Sp",d:"Sp2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:57,question:"Three drops of a 1.0 mol dm-3 solution of Na OH are added to 20cm3 of a solution of pH8.4. the pH of the resulting solution will be",option:{a:"Greater than 8.4",b:"Unaltered",c:"Close to that of pure water",d:"Less than 8.4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:288,question:"To a solution of an unknown compound, a little dilute Tetraoxosulphate (IV) acid was added with some freshly prepared (II) Tetraoxosulphate (VI) Solution. The brown ring observed after the addition of a stream of concentrated  Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid confirmed the presence of",option:{a:"CI",b:"SO",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:138,question:"The solubility in mol dm-3 of 20g of CuSO4 dissolved in 100g of water at 1800C is  [Cu = 64, S = 32, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.13",b:"0.25",c:"1.25",d:"2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:128,question:"It is difficult to achieve an orderly arrangement of the molecules of a gas because they",option:{a:"Have no definite shape",b:"Have little force attraction between them",c:"Can collide with one another in the container",d:"Are too small in size"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:156,question:"Aluminium hydroxide is used in the dyeing industry as a",option:{a:"Salt",b:"Dye",c:"Mordant",d:"Dispersant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:280,question:"6AgNO3(aq)  +  PH3(g) +    3H2O(l)      →    6Ag(s)+   H3PO3(aq)   +    6HNO3(aq)  In the reaction above, the reducing agent is",option:{a:"H2O(l)",b:"PH3(g)",c:"AgNO3(aq)",d:"HNO3(AQ)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:84,question:"A gas exerts pressure on its container because",option:{a:"Some of its molecules are moving faster than others",b:"Of the collision of the molecules with each other",c:"Of the mass of the molecules of gas",d:"The molecules of a gas collide with the walls of the container"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:295,question:"Which of the following is used as fuel in miners’ lamp",option:{a:"Ethyne",b:"Ethane",c:"Ethane",d:"Ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:274,question:"Coffee stains can best be removed by",option:{a:"Turpentine",b:"A solution of borax in water",c:"Ammonia solution",d:"Kerosene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:216,question:"H2(g)  +  Br2(g) →  2BHr(g)  The reaction above is carried out at 250C. If Δ H is kJ mol-1 and   Δ S is -106J mol-1K-1 the reaction will",option:{a:"Proceed spontaneously at lower temperatures",b:"Not proceed spontaneously at the given temperature",c:"Proceed spontaneously at the given temperature",d:"[proceed in the reverse direction at the given temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:92,question:"Farmlands affected by crude –oil spillage can be decontaminated by",option:{a:"Adding acidic solutions",b:"Using aerobic bacteria",c:"Pouring water on the affected area",d:"Burning off the oil from the area"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:108,question:"The salt that will form a precipitate soluble in excess ammonia solution is",option:{a:"Ca(NO3)2",b:"Cu(NO3)2",c:"Mg(NO3)2",d:"Al(NO3)3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:97,question:"Which of the following will change when a catalyst is added to a chemical reaction",option:{a:"The activation energy",b:"The potential energy of the reactants",c:"The heat of reaction",d:"The potential energy of the products"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:54,question:"The furring of kettles is caused by the presence in water of",option:{a:"Calcium trioxocarbonate(IV)",b:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",c:"CALCIUM HYDROXIDE",d:"Calcium hydrofentrioxocarbonate(IV)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:287,question:"2H2(g) +    O2(g)  ⇌ 2H2O(g)    ΔH   =  - ve  What happens to the equilibrium constant of the reaction above if the temperature is increased?",option:{a:"It becomes zero",b:"It decreases",c:"It increases",d:"It is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:227,question:"The order in which a mixture of sand ammonium chloride and sodium chloride can be separated is",option:{a:"Sublimation   dissolution  filtration  evaporation",b:"Dissolution  dryness  filtration  evaporation",c:"Filtration  sublimation  evaporation  dryness",d:"Dissolution  filtration  sublimation  evaporation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:239,question:"One mole of a hydrocarbon contains 36g of carbon and its vapour density is 20. The structure of the hydrocarbon is",option:{a:"CH3CH2CH3",b:"CH3CH = CH2",c:"CH3CH2C = CH",d:"CH3C = CH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:304,question:"The compound that is used as an anaesthetic is",option:{a:"CHCI3",b:"CH2C2",c:"CH3CI",d:"CCI4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:30,question:"Fermentation is the",option:{a:"Breaking down of carbohydrate to glucose",b:"Conversion of sugar to alcohol in the presence of yeast",c:"Breaking down of sugar to carbohydrate",d:"Conversion of alcohol to sugar in the presence of yeast"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:271,question:"Permanent hardness of water can be removed by",option:{a:"Adding slaked lime",b:"Adding caustic soda",c:"Boiling",d:"Filtration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:233,question:"A difference between chemical and physical change is that in a chemical change",option:{a:"Heat is supplied",b:" A new substance is formed",c:"Oxygen is consumed",d:"A reversible process occurs"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:131,question:"The shape of the s-orbital is",option:{a:"Spherical",b:"Elliptical",c:"Spiral",d:"Circular"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:193,question:"Equal moles of ethyne and hydrogen iodide react to give",option:{a:"CH2 = CH2",b:"CH2 = CHI",c:"CH2 – CHI",d:"CH2 – CI3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:50,question:"Steam changes the colour of anhydrous cobalt(II) chloride from",option:{a:"White to red",b:"Blue to white",c:"White to green",d:"Blue to pink"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:107,question:"Which of the following statements is true of sulphur (IV) oxide",option:{a:"It forms Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid with water",b:"It is an odourless gas",c:"It is an acid anhydride",d:"It forms white precipitate with acidified barium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:218,question:"The ion that can be used as an oxidizing agent is",option:{a:"Fe3+",b:"F-",c:"Ca2+",d:"Au3+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:79,question:"3Cu  +  pHNO3  → 3Cu(NO3)2  +  4H2O  + xNO   In the equation above, the values of p and x respectively are",option:{a:"1 and 3",b:"2 and 3",c:"6 and 2",d:"8 and 2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:247,question:"Water has the ability to dissolve almost all substances because its molecule has a structure with",option:{a:"One positive end and one neutral end",b:"Two positive ends",c:"One positive end and one negative end",d:"Two negative ends"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:27,question:"As the concentration of an electrolyte reduces, the conductivity",option:{a:"Reduces to zero",b:"Decreases",c:"Increases",d:"Is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:68,question:"A rock sample was added to cold dilute HNMO3. The gas evolved was passed into a solution of acidified K2Cr2O7 and the solution turned green. The rock sample contains",option:{a:"NO3-",b:"Cl-",c:"SO42-",d:"SO32-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:238,question:"An example of aliphatic unsaturated hydrocarbon is",option:{a:"Butanol",b:"Propene",c:"Pentane",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:47,question:"The formula CH2O for ethanoic acid is regarded as its",option:{a:"General formula",b:"Structural formula",c:"Molecular formula",d:"Empirical formula"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:3,question:"A particle that contains 9 protons, 10 neutrons and 10electrons is a",option:{a:"Neghative ion",b:"Positive ion",c:"Neutral atom of a non metal",d:"Neutral atom of a metal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:178,question:"The most suitable metal that can be used as a lightening  conductor is",option:{a:"Aluminium",b:"Iron",c:"Copper",d:"Silver"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:1,question:"25cm3 of a gas X contains Zmolecules at 150C and 75mmHg. How many molecules will 25cmm3 of another gas Y contain at the same temperature and pressure",option:{a:"2Y",b:"2Z",c:"Z",d:"Y"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:212,question:"What will happen if an aluminum spoon is used to stir a solution of iron (II) trioxonitrate(V)",option:{a:"The spoon will be reduced while the iron(II) ions will be oxidized",b:"The spoon will be oxidized while the iron (II) ions will be reduced to the metal",c:"The spoon will be reduced",d:"The spoon will increase in size"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:51,question:"Which of the following solutions containing only hydroxyl ions will liberate hydrogen gas when reacted with magnesium metal",option:{a:"1.0 x 10-2 mol dm-3",b:"1.0 x 10-4 mol dm -3",c:"1.0 x 10-5 mol dm-3",d:"1.0 x 10-12 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:23,question:"C(s) + 2S (g)  → CS2 (g)      Δ H = +89kJ mol-1. The chemical equation above implies that",option:{a:"Each of carbon and sulphur has 89kJ of energy",b:"Both carbon and sulphur contribute 89kJ of energy",c:"89kJ of energy is released",d:"89kJ is absorbed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:161,question:"The alkyl group can be represented by the general formula",option:{a:"CnH2n+1",b:"CnH2n",c:"CnH2n+2",d:"CnH2n-2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:299,question:"The final products of the reaction between methane and chloride in the presence of ultraviolet light are hydrogen chloride and",option:{a:"Dichloromethane",b:"Tetrachloromethane",c:"Chloromethane",d:"Trichloromethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:162,question:"An isomer of C5H12 is",option:{a:"Butane",b:"2-methylbutane",c:"2-methylprpane",d:"2-ethylbutane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:267,question:"The stability of the noble gases is due to the fact that they",option:{a:"Have duplet or octet electron configurations",b:"Belong to group zero of the periodic table",c:"Are volatile in nature",d:"Have no electron in their outermost shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:15,question:"The chemiocal used for coagulation in water purification is",option:{a:"Aluminum tetraoxosulphate(VI)",b:"Copper tetratoxosulphate (VI)",c:"Sodium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",d:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate (VI)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:106,question:"Hydrogen can be displaced form a hot alkaline solution by",option:{a:"Fe",b:"Cu",c:"Ca",d:"Sn"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:189,question:"The shape of the hydrocarbon compound CH4 is",option:{a:"Square planar",b:"Tetrahedral",c:"Planar",d:"Linear"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:300,question:"The correct order of increasing boiling points of the following  compounds C3H7OH, C7H16 and C4H10 is",option:{a:"C4H10  →  C7H16 → C3H7OH",b:"C7H16 → C3H7OH → C4H16",c:"C4H10  → C3H7OH  → C4H10",d:"C3H7OH →  C4H10  → C7H16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:21,question:"What current in amperes will deposit 2.7g of aluminium in 2 hours [Al = 27, f = 96500 C mol-1]",option:{a:"32",b:"8",c:"4",d:"16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:192,question:"Sugar is separated from its impurities by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Evaporation",c:"Precipitation",d:"Crystallization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:151,question:"The allotrope of carbon used in the decolourization of sugar is",option:{a:"Graphite",b:"Soot",c:"Charcoal",d:"Lampblack"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:20,question:"Which of the following best explains the increase in the rate of a chemical reaction as the temperature rises",option:{a:"The bonds in the reacting molecules are more readily broken",b:"The molecules collisions become more violent",c:"A lower proportion of the molecules has the necessary minimum energy to react",d:"The collision frequency of the molecules increases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:226,question:"What is the mola. Mass of a substance, if 0.4 mole of the substance has a mass of 25.0g",option:{a:"6.3g",b:"40.0g",c:"62.5g",d:"2.5g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:34,question:"Catalytic hydrogenation of benzene produces",option:{a:"Oil",b:"Cyclohexane",c:"Cycloexane",d:"Margarine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:72,question:"The intermediate product formed when ethanol is progressively oxidized to ethanoic acid with potassium heptaoxodichromate(VI) is",option:{a:"Ethanol",b:"Methanol",c:"Butanal",d:"Propanal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:298,question:"Which of the following is used to hasten the ripening of fruit",option:{a:"Ethanol",b:"Ethyne",c:"Ethane",d:"Ethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:160,question:"Oxyacetylene flame is used for iron-welding because it",option:{a:" makes the iron metal solidity very quickly",b:"Combines with oxygen to give a pop sound",c:"Evolves a lot of heat when burnt",d:"Dissociates to produce carbon (IV) oxide and oxygen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:74,question:"The boiling of fat and aqueous caustic soda is referred as",option:{a:"Saponification",b:"Esterification",c:"Acidification",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:296,question:"Which of the following organic compounds is very soluble in water",option:{a:"C2H2",b:"C2H4",c:"CH3COOC2H5",d:"CH3COOH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:214,question:"2H2 + O2  → 2H2O  ΔH = -571Kj  In equation above, how much heat will be liberated if 12.0g of hydrogen is burnt in excess oxygen?",option:{a:"-1713kJ",b:"+1142kJ",c:"-571kJ",d:"-1142kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:270,question:"A noble gas with a high power of fog penetration used in aerodrome beacons is",option:{a:"Argon",b:"Helium",c:"Neon",d:"Krypton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:8,question:"An element X with relative atomic mass 16.2 contains two isotopes      X  with relative abundance of 90% and      X with relative abundance of 10%. The value of m is",option:{a:"16",b:"18",c:"12",d:"14"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:256,question:"Which of the following typically represents a photochemical reaction",option:{a:"Conversion of dinitrogen (IV) oxide to nitrogen(IV) oxide",b:"Conversion of silver halides to grey metallic silver",c:"Decomposition of calcium hydroxide to its oxide",d:"Formation of water from hydrogen and oxygen molecules"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:102,question:"When sugar is dissolved in tea, the reaction is always accompanied by",option:{a:"Positive entropy change",b:"Negative entropy change",c:"No entropy change",d:"A minimum entropy change"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:164,question:"Which of these reagents can confirm the presence of a triple bond",option:{a:"Bromine water",b:"Acidified KMnO4 ",c:"Copper (I) chloride",d:"Bromine gas"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:19,question:"A metal M displaces zinc from zinc chloride solution. This shows that",option:{a:"M is more electronegative than zinc",b:"Zinc is above hydrogen in the series",c:"M is more electropositive than zinc",d:"Electrons flow from zinc to M"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:180,question:"When pure aluminum metal is heated to red hot in the presence of nitrogen gas, the compound formed is",option:{a:"AI2N",b:"AIN",c:"AI2N2",d:"AI2N3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:169,question:"The gas that can be dried using concentrated Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid is",option:{a:"Ammonia",b:"Hydrogen bromide",c:"Sulphur (IV) oxide",d:"Hydrogen sulphide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:43,question:"Which of the followinig respresents hybridization in ethyne?",option:{a:"Sp2",b:"Sp2d",c:"Sp3",d:"sp"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:203,question:"The solubility curve shows the variation of solute concentration with",option:{a:"Volume",b:"Vapour density",c:"Pressure",d:"Temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:165,question:"Vulcanization involves the removal of",option:{a:"A monomer",b:"The single bond",c:"The double bond",d:"A polymer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:262,question:"Calculate the percentage by mass of nitrogen in calcium trioxonitrate (V)   {Ca = 40, N = 14, O = 16}",option:{a:"13.10%",b:"17.10%",c:"27.60%",d:"8.5"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:87,question:"A consequence of global warming is",option:{a:"Air pollution",b:"Water pollution",c:"Increased humidity",d:"Flooding"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:167,question:` Alkanol + Alkanoic acid ⇌  Ester + water.
The reverse reaction of the equation above is known as
`,option:{a:"Hydrolysis",b:"Saponification",c:"Hydration",d:"Fermentation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:281,question:"The IUPAC nomencalatyre of the compound LiAIH4 is",option:{a:"Aluminium tetrahydrido lithium",b:"Tetrahydrido lithium aluminate (III)",c:"Lithium aluminium hydride",d:"Lithium tetrahydridoaluminate (III)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:35,question:"A trihydric alkanol is",option:{a:"glycerol",b:"phenol",c:"glycol",d:"ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:250,question:"Dynamic equilibrium describes a situation where",option:{a:"A reaction gives back the reactants",b:"Reactants are converted to products",c:"The concentration of reactants and products is equal",d:"Both forward and reverse reaction proceed at the same rate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:145,question:"In the electrolysis of brine, the anode is",option:{a:"Platinum",b:"Copper",c:"Zinc",d:"Carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:225,question:"The solution that will conduct the highest amount of electricity is",option:{a:"2.0 moldm-3 of ethanoic acid",b:"0.5 mol dm-3 of ethanoic acid",c:"2.0 mol dm-3 of hydrochloric acid",d:"0.5 moldm-3 of hydrochloric acid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:261,question:"Which of the following is an example of a mixture",option:{a:"Blood",b:"Sand",c:"Washing soda",d:"Common salt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:279,question:"Which of the following salts is slightly soluble in water",option:{a:"CaSO4",b:"Na2CO3",c:"PbCl2",d:"AgCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:59,question:"25cm3 of a 0.2mol dm-3 solution of Na2CO3 requires 20cm3 of  solution of HCl for neutralization. The concentration of the solution is",option:{a:"0.6 mol dm-3",b:"0.5 mol dm-3",c:"0.4 mol dm-3",d:"0.2 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:70,question:"The most important use of hydrogen is in the",option:{a:"Hydrogenation of oils",b:"Manufacture of methyl alcohol",c:"Manufacture of ammonia",d:"Manufacture of ethyl alcohol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:22,question:"Ethanoic acid is",option:{a:"Tribasic",b:"Unionizeable",c:"Monobasic",d:"Dibasic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:124,question:"A chemical reaction is always associated with",option:{a:"An increase in the composition of one of the substances",b:"A change in the volume of the reactants",c:"A change in the nature of the reactants",d:"The formation of new substances"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:63,question:"Which of the following statements is true of a proton.",option:{a:"The total mass of the protons in a particular nucleus always half the nuclear mass",b:"The mass of a proton is 1840 times the mass of an electron",c:"The mass proton is 1.0008g",d:"The mass of a proton is one-twelfth the molar mass of carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:223,question:"IN which of the following is the oxidation number of sulphur equal to -2",option:{a:"H2S",b:"SO3",c:"S8",d:"SO2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:139,question:"Calcium Tetraoxosulphate(VI) dissolves in water only sparingly to form a",option:{a:"Solution",b:"Suspension",c:"Precipitate",d:"Colloid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:158,question:"Transition metals posses variable oxidation states because they have",option:{a:"Electrons in the d orbitals",b:"Electrons in the s orbitals",c:"A variable number of electrons in the p orbitals",d:"Partially filled p orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:163,question:"A characteristic of the alkane family is",option:{a:"Addition reaction",b:"Elimination reaction",c:"Substitution reaction",d:"Neutralization reaction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:6,question:"Milikan’s contribution to the development of atomic theory is the determination of",option:{a:"Charge on electron",b:"Positive rays",c:"Charge to amss ratio",d:"Cathode rays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:26,question:"When ΔH is negative, a reaction is said to be",option:{a:"Ionic",b:"Reversible",c:"Exothermic",d:"Endothermic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:116,question:"The formula for ethyl butanoate is",option:{a:"C3H7COOC2H5",b:"C2H5COOC3H7",c:"C4H9COOC2H5",d:"C2H5COOC4H9"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:282,question:"Iron can be protected from corrosion by coating the surface with",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Zinc",d:"Gold"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:231,question:"A particle that contain s 11protons, 12 neutrons and 10 electrons is probably a",option:{a:"Metallic ion",b:"Non-metallic ion",c:"Neutral metal",d:"Neutral non-metal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:119,question:"A compound contains 40.0% carbon, 6.7% hydrogen and 53.3% oxygen. If the molar mass of the compound is 180, find the molecular formula  [H = 1, C = 12, O = 16]",option:{a:"CH2O",b:"C3H6O3",c:"C6H12O6",d:"C6H6O3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:153,question:"Which steam is passed over red-hot carbon, the substances produced are",option:{a:"Hydrogen and trioxocarbonate(IV) acid",b:"Hydrogen, oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Hydrogen and carbon (II) oxide",d:"Hydrogen and carbon (IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:18,question:"P(g) + O(g)    ⇌ 3R(s)  +  S(g)   ΔH is negative which of the following will increase the yield of R",option:{a:"Using a larger closed vessel",b:"Increasing the temperature",c:"Removing some S",d:"Adding a positive catalyst"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:78,question:"The filter in a cigarette reduces the nicotine content by",option:{a:"Burning",b:"Adsorption",c:"Evaporation",d:"Absorption"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:99,question:"When at equilibrium, which of the reactions below will shift to the right if the pressure is increased and the temperature is kept constant",option:{a:" 2SO3(g)  ⇌  2SO2(g)  +  O2(g)",b:" 2CO2(g)  ⇌ 2CO(g)  +  O2(g)",c:" 2H2(g)  +  O2(g) ⇌  2H2O(g)",d:" 2NO(g)   ⇌ N2(g)  +  O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:11,question:"Deliquenscent substances are used for",option:{a:"Cooling",b:"Wetting",c:"Melting",d:"Drying"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:185,question:"The density of a certain gas is 1.98g dm-3 at s.t.p. What is the molecular mass of the gas   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm-3]",option:{a:"26.0g",b:"31.0g",c:"54.0g",d:"44.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:264,question:"The volume of a gas is Vcm3 at P mm Hg. What is the new volume of the gas if the pressure is reduced to half at constant temperature",option:{a:"2 V cm3",b:"V  2cm3",c:"V cm3",d:"4 V cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:301,question:"One of the major uses of Alkanes is",option:{a:"In the hydrogenation of oils",b:"In the textile industries",c:"In the production of plastics",d:"As domestic and industrial fuels"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:244,question:"The produce of the combustion of candle wax are",option:{a:"Carbon(IV) oxide and water",b:"Oxygen and water",c:"Hydrogen and water",d:"Carbon(II)oxide an d water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:183,question:"What is the valence shell electron configuration of the element with atomic number 17",option:{a:"1s22s22p63s23p5",b:"1s22s22p63s23p4",c:"3s23p5",d:"2s22p6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:75,question:"What volume of oxygen is produced from the decomposition of 2 moles of KClO3 at s.t.p   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4 dm3]",option:{a:"22.4 dm3",b:"33.6 dm3",c:"44.8 dm3",d:"67.2 dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:t};export{t as data,n as default,e as message,a as status,o as subject,i as total};
